amcharts.com 2019-04-27

# amCharts Privacy Policy - amCharts

Version: 2018052501

This privacy policy sets out how amCharts uses and protects any information that you give amCharts when you use this website.

amCharts is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

This policy is effective from 2018-05-25 (May 25th 2018). amCharts may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. If that happens, we will notify you when you next visit amcharts.com and will ask you to consent again. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes.  If you continue using the website after the updates, we consider that you agree with the changes.

## What we collect

When you register for an account on amcharts.com website we collect the following information:

  * Your first and last names;
  * Your email address.

When you acquire a license for amCharts software, we collect the following information:

  * Name of your company or organization;
  * Your first and last names;
  * Ordered products and services;
  * Contact information including physical and email addresses.

When you subscribe to any of our email newsletters we collect the following information:

  * Your email address.

When you browse amCharts websites the following information is collected by a 3rd party analytical service:

  * Your IP address;
  * Information about your setup, like browser and operating system version.

When you email or otherwise contact amCharts helpdesk the following information is collected by a 3rd party helpdesk service:

  * Your first and last names;
  * Your email address;
  * Subject and content of your message including all attachments.

## What we do with the information we gather

We require this information to sell our goods and services to you, to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * Internal record keeping;
  * We may use the information to provide access to services you subscribed for or downloads of software you have purchased;
  * We may use this information to inform you about expiring subscriptions;
  * We may occasionally send you an email about important changes to the amCharts software or services you are already using or related to it, such as new versions or similar products;
  * We may periodically send you an email for newsletters you have **explicitly** subscribed for;
  * For analytical purposes so that we can improve our websites and services by analyzing actual behavior of our users;
  * For being able to provide support via our web/email-based helpdesk;
  * To make our website and services better.

## Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

Should any data breaches become known to us, we will notify responsible authorities as soon as possible, including technical details of the breach as well as extend of personal data affected. In addition, if the stolen data contains unencrypted personal data, we will inform you personally as soon as possible and within set timeframe by the laws.

## Where is your information held

Information is held on the servers operated by credible third parties like MediaTemple, Inc. and Amazon Web Services, Inc. physically located in the European Union or United States of America.

## How long do we keep your information

**Data** | **Disposed**  
---|---  
User account on amcharts.com and related data | 26 months after its last use (login) or upon request  
Information about orders and related data | Upon request (deleting such info might forfeit your right to access purchased products or services)  
Anonymous analytical site usage data | After 26 months  
Communications with amCharts helpdesk including emails, web messages and chat, as well as related attachments and data | Upon request  
Subscriptions to email newsletters | Upon request  
  
## How we use cookies

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

## List of cookies used on amCharts websites

**Cookie** | **Purpose** | **Expires**  
---|---|---  
Cookies used by amCharts  
PHPSESSID | To maintain user session (keep signed in user) | When browser window is closed  
amdocs_* | To maintain preferences in documentation (preferred language, class reference search) | 12 months  
amcharts_* | To maintain your selection preferences, such as agreement to our privacy and cookie policy and its version | 12 months  
Cookies used by Google Analytics  
_ga | Used to distinguish users. | 2 years  
_gid | Used to distinguish users. | 24 hours  
_gat | Used to throttle request rate. If Google Analytics is deployed via Google Tag Manager, this cookie will be named _dc_gtm_<property-id>. | 1 minute  
AMP_TOKEN | Contains a token that can be used to retrieve a Client ID from AMP Client ID service. Other possible values indicate opt-out, inflight request or an error retrieving a Client ID from AMP Client ID service. | 30 seconds to 1 year  
_gac_<property-id> | Contains campaign related information for the user, linking Google Analytics and AdWords accounts. | 90 days  
Cookies used by MailChimp  
MCPopupClosed | Indicates that subscription popup was open and closed, so that no assets for it are already loaded and do not require to be loaded again if form is displayed again. | 12 months  
  
## Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## Information provided during purchase

amCharts license and service purchases are conducted by a company cleverbridge AG, incorporated within EU (Germany). cleverbridge AG acts as a data processor. Please refer to their [Privacy policy](https://www.cleverbridge.com/corporate/privacy-policy/) for further details and conditions.

## Controlling your personal information

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to [contact@amcharts.com](mailto:contact@amcharts.com).

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

## List of data sub-processors

amCharts makes use of the following 3rd party data sub-processors:

**Entity Name** | **Purpose** | **Entity Country**  
---|---|---  
Amazon Web Services, Inc. | Public website content served to website visitors may be stored with Amazon Web Services, Inc., (“AWS”) and transmitted by AWS, to website visitors, to expedite transmission. 

amCharts also uses AWS to store data backups which may contain information about you. Such backup information has a rotation mechanism which adheres to the timeframes for personal data removal as required by laws.

| United States   
Go Daddy Operating Company LLC (Media Temple service) | amCharts uses Media Temple services to store the data as well as publish amCharts websites as well as other content delivery. | United States  
Cloudflare, Inc. | Cloudflare, Inc. (“Cloudflare”) provides content distribution, security and DNS services for web traffic transmitted to and from the Services. 

amCharts uses Cloudlare service to efficiently manage web traffic and load on our servers.

Cloudflare does not have direct access to user data except URLs being accessed by user and user’s IP address.

| United States  
The Rocket Science Group LLC (MailChimp service) | Delivery of email newsletters to subscribed users. 

amCharts uses The Rocket Science Group LLC (“MailChimp”) to deliver newsletter and other content to users who gave permission for it.

| United States  
cleverbridge AG | amCharts uses cleverbridge AG (“cleverbridge”) to process orders for amCharts’ products and services. 

amCharts is not involved in the purchase process. Once user is transferred to cleverbridge’s website to complete the purchase, cleverbridge’s own privacy policy kicks in which is also adheres to applicable EU and International laws.

| Germany  
Google Inc. | Collection of anonymous analytical data of usage of amCharts websites. Among logged data is user’s IP address, however it’s not associated with any other identifiable user’s data such as name or email address. | United States
